♪
Well, shall we be off, then?
FRIEREN: BEYOND JOURNEY'S END
[cart wheels rattling]
♪
[Frieren sighs] It's unusually
warm today.
[STARK] It is. I'll take
the bonus warmth.
But I would prefer
some cold, hard cash,
if you know what I mean.
[FERN] Four measly coins.
We'll have to look for work
in the next town.
We haven't even
gotten there yet
and you're thinking
about work?
I'd like to survive,
wouldn't you?
Unless we stay two steps ahead,
our journey will come
to a premature end.
I suppose that is true.
So work it is.
I hope we find
something suitable.
Funny.
This feels familiar.
[FERN] Thank you very much
for the ride, sir.
[COACHMAN] Don't mention it!
It's not every day I have
a first-class mage in my cart.
I could breathe easy,
thanks to you.
Goodness. You'll be on the road
to Ende for a while.
Most folks would never dare
venture so far from home.
To all of us in that camp,
a journey like yours
sounds unimaginably long.
[Frieren chuckles softly]
[FRIEREN] Maybe it will be.
[♪ opening theme song playing]
FRIEREN: BEYOND JOURNEY'S END
29 YEARS AFTER THE DEATH
OF HIMMEL THE HERO,
IN THE SAUM MARSHES, LOCATED
IN THE NORTHERN LANDS
♪
[STARK] Uh? [grunts]
[Stark sighs]
It's not much,
but I caught one.
[FERN] I'll add it
to our breakfast.
♪
Don't say anything.
I already know.
-[rustling]
-[FRIEREN] Um...
How odd.
It should be
around here somewhere.
She's up?
Isn't it too early for her?
She woke up curious
about something.
And curiosity knows no clock.
[STARK] Hmm.
You praised her, didn't you?
Well, of course.
[FRIEREN] Found it.
I had a feeling
it was a big one.
[Frieren chuckles softly]
[STARK] That's a pretty stone.
But what makes it so special?
Here.
[STARK] Uh...
Hold on.
I can't conjure fire.
[FRIEREN] It's called
a magic-nullifying crystal.
It's a mineral that
neutralizes magical effects.
[STARK] Hmm.
[FRIEREN]
A specimen of this purity
has an effective radius
of three meters.
Stark, step over there for me,
will you?
[STARK] Huh? Okay.
Uh? Here goes.
This is an extremely rare find.
Even if it were pebble-sized,
it would be worth
several pieces of gold.
A crystal this large
could buy us a mansion.
Sign me up.
[Frieren chuckles softly]
That's great,
but it blocks our magic.
Travelling with it would
render us completely useless.
Keep it and we're
dead men walking.
'Tis the burden we bear.
I don't bear it.
Please get rid of the rock.
If a monster attacked right now,
we'd all be wiped out.
Fine. But it would be
a shame
to leave it without sharing
its flashiest property.
It's truly a terrific show.
When you imbue these stones
with a large amount of mana...
[Stark gasps]
[FRIEREN]...they glow
with an impressive light.
[STARK] It's blinding me.
[FERN]
Just throw that thing away.
♪
It's still glowing.
[STARK] Keep up our pace,
and we'll reach
the next village today.
That's good, right?
We're finally getting close
to the Northern Plateau.
The plateau is very far away.
We still must venture
through a vast forest
and volcanic area.
A volcanic area?
Sounds like we're in
for some real danger.
[FRIEREN]
I wouldn't say that.
There hasn't been
an eruption in centuries.
These days, it's a relatively
safe hot spring region.
A hot spring sounds nice.
It feels like
it's been a lifetime
since I had a warm bath.
We're long overdue
for some rest and relaxation.
[FRIEREN] Strange.
Stop for a moment.
The earth here
is exceptionally thin.
-[rumbling]
-[Stark screams]
Just as I thought.
It seems we've stumbled
upon an underground cave.
The ground of a marshland
can never be trusted.
Hey. Mistress Frieren?
Oh...
-Land rump first.
-[STARK] Wait, what?
[Stark screaming]
[Stark groans]
[Stark screams]
[FRIEREN] No wonder we found
that magic-nullifying crystal
on the surface.
I've never seen
a deposit this large before.
[STARK] Please get off me.
♪
This cave is practically filled
to the brim with them.
If we brought it
all back with us,
we'd be rich as kings.
I'm afraid we're not
up to the task.
[STARK] Oh.
Magic-nullifying crystal
is one of the hardest materials
in existence.
That, and unlike most stones
I've encountered,
it can neither be cut
nor processed using magic.
[STARK] Hmm.
[STARK] Hm?
[FRIEREN]
Some treasures of nature
are simply
out of humanity's reach.
In any case, we're not climbing
our way out of here.
Let's look for another exit.
Hey, why the face?
We're counting
on you now, Stark.
Don't fail.
Since we can't use magic
to defend ourselves, down here,
we're helpless young ladies.
Young ladies?
Careful.
I still haven't forgiven
your "old hag" quip
from the dragon duel.
Okay, I'm sorry.
Expert grudge-holding.
♪
[STARK]
When I imagined our journey,
I never pictured camping
-in a place like this.
-[Frieren snores]
[FERN] This cave complex
is immense.
Unbelievably so.
And I'm not fond of the number
of animal bones we've found.
According to Mistress Frieren,
this might be the den
of a giant monster.
I'm amazed she can
sleep so soundly.
[STARK]
Not a care in the world.
[FERN] Even down here,
she still seems
to be having fun.
I'm far too afraid to join in.
I can't even detect mana.
I feel so isolated and helpless.
It's like I've been plunged
into total darkness.
I'm here.
-[loud rumbling]
-[gasping]
[both gasp]
[FERN] A monster!
Frieren? Wake up! Now!
[FRIEREN]
A venomous apex dragon.
Venomous?
It's a terrible matchup
for you.
You'll die from poison again.
I didn't die the first time.
And it doesn't matter.
I've got to fight it, don't I?
I can't believe you were
drooling like a baby.
-How could you sleep so--
-I could sleep so soundly
because I trust you
with my life, Stark.
[STARK] Hmm.
That feeling
solidified within me
the very moment I recruited you
to be our warrior.
A party can't function properly
without complete
and utter trust.
Why would you trust someone
whose only skill
is running away?
If I had a choice,
I would run right now.
[FRIEREN] Is that so?
Shall we run away together then?
Stark, Fern,
please close your eyes.
[EISEN] Himmel.
If you truly trust me
with your life,
I question your sanity.
[HIMMEL] Hm?
[EISEN] Your faith should
not be so easily won.
[chuckles softly]
[EISEN]
I abandoned my village and fled.
Is that so?
Fine. If you want to run,
we can run away together.
[EISEN] Hmm.
We're a party.
We'll follow where you lead.
[explosion]
[roars]
[grunts]
[exclaims]
[Eisen scoffs, grunts]
[Himmel sighs]
Running sounds like a good plan.
[panting]
Scoundrel! You took the pebble
and left the priest
with the boulder!
Because the pebble will complain
you stink of liquor!
[Himmel chuckles]
[panting]
♪
[Stark panting]
That was scary.
But running away as a team
isn't so miserable.
[STARK] Yeah.
[Stark continues panting]
[FRIEREN]
Shall we be off, then?
[STARK] Frieren.
What now?
I can't get my legs
to take another step.
EPISODE 29: SHALL WE GO, THEN?
29 YEARS AFTER THE DEATH
OF HIMMEL THE HERO,
IN THE GREAT SANFT FOREST,
LOCATED IN THE NORTHERN LANDS
[STARK]
Will this be enough for lunch?
Maybe I should have
picked some more.
Uh?
You're kidding!
I'm the first one back?
I guess I was too quick
with the gathering, huh?
Well, it wouldn't hurt
to get some fishing in.
I'm gonna bag a big one
this time. I can feel it.
[Frieren shivering]
[FRIEREN] So cold.
[FERN] We'll reach
the hot springs soon enough.
There. Good as new.
That was given to you
by Stark, right?
A mirrored-lotus bracelet
is quite the gift.
I also cleaned off
the hairpin you gave me.
All bright and shiny again.
You're careful
with your staff, too.
You seem to relish the ritual
of maintaining
your equipment, Fern.
You think so?
You've been smiling
this whole time.
[Fern chuckles softly]
[FERN] Maybe I care so much
because they were gifts.
I lost everything,
from my home to the objects
that filled it, to war.
Perhaps a part of me
just cherishes the chance
to own things
with meaning again.
Then it was
well worth the headache
picking it out for you.
It took you a long time
to choose.
How do you know about that?
-[chuckles]
-[rustling]
[gasps]
[STARK] Uh...
Pervert!
I am so, so sorry.
I had no idea the two of you
would be bathing, I swear.
I'm obviously not angry.
And there. All done.
[FRIEREN] Hmm.
Oh.
How confounding.
Something's not right here.
[STARK] Like what?
Am I alone in feeling
an awkward tension in the air?
[STARK] Definitely not.
So you're finally
starting to pick up
on the more
touchy-feely stuff, huh?
That's some major growth.
[FRIEREN] This seems to happen
with some frequency.
Perhaps you two
are simply ill-matched.
[STARK]
I wouldn't go that far.
Listen, Stark.
[STARK] Hm?
[FRIEREN]
If you're uncomfortable,
you can always just say so.
You wouldn't be in this party
to begin with
if I hadn't forced you
to join us.
If you hadn't forced me?
That's not why I--
[FERN]
We're at a crossroads.
[FRIEREN] It seems this path
leads to the Northern Plateau,
while Neutral Harbor
lies down the other.
Frieren, over there.
Does that look like an inn
to you?
[FRIEREN] This is
a frequently traveled road.
At least we won't have
to camp out tonight.
[bell dinging]
[WIRBEL] Oh?
Well, look who it is!
-[FRIEREN] Hm?
-[laughs]
Seems our reunion came
sooner than expected.
By the way, Stark,
thanks again for your help
with that Fresser business.
Sure thing, Wirbel.
You seem to be well.
Ultimately, I decided
to travel home by sea.
News from the north is dire.
The demons are acting up
in the far reaches.
I need to get up there
as fast as possible.
I'm with these two
until we make it to the capital,
that is.
He's anxious about seasickness.
The whining's incessant.
I thought you were
a grown man, Wirbel.
You're far too old for whining.
Think so?
Here I thought I was still in
the full flower of my youth.
I'm only a recent departee
from my twenties.
[STARK] Funny. All you old guys
suffer from the same delusions.
[WIRBEL] Anyway, Stark.
Have you had time to think
about my proposition?
Proposition?
The situation up north has gone
from bad to worse, quick.
Reliable front-line fighters
are in serious demand.
You're free to say no.
But we could really use
your axe, Stark.
Just for a few years
until things stabilize.
It's like I told you before,
Wirbel.
My services
have been pledged already.
That's fair.
But it's not in my nature
to give up easy.
When it comes
to the safety of the north,
I would do anything.
[STARK] Uh...
Well, Frieren.
Can I work on him a bit?
-Wait--
-You may do as you wish.
[WIRBEL] Hmm.
Mistress Frieren.
-[ALL] Cheers.
-[Wirbel chuckles]
I'm telling you, Stark,
I'm a fun guy to be around.
[FRIEREN]
Seems he's having fun.
-[SCHARF] Indeed.
-[STARK] Appreciate the offer...
I'm sure it's a nice
change of pace for him.
Stark must find our party
somewhat restrictive
by comparison.
[WIRBEL]...coins
and maidens' hearts.
[STARK] Yeah, that doesn't sound
like my kind of thing.
[door opens]
[door closes]
So... how'd it go?
I turned down Wirbel's offer,
if that's what you mean.
[FERN] Are you certain?
You don't have to stay.
You know,
I don't think either of you
realize why I'm here.
When I first met you
and Frieren, I was at my limit.
I couldn't see
the meaning in it anymore.
Truth be told,
I was ready to cut and run.
Leave that village
to fend for itself.
Real heroic, huh?
Frieren doesn't get it.
She's under the impression
that she forced me
to join this party
against my will.
But she's wrong.
♪
We just met. But...
I don't think you'll run.
[STARK] Your encouragement
relit a fire in me
that had been cold
for a long time.
In that moment, I knew
the right thing to do
was to go with you.
Maybe you're just too modest
to have noticed it.
But Frieren isn't
the only reason
my cowardly hide is still here.
You're also to blame.
[Stark chuckles]
I promise
I'm not going anywhere.
[Fern chuckles softly]
-[soft thudding]
-[Ferns gasps]
So please try
and be nicer to me, okay?
Very well then.
Come here, Stark.
Time for head pats.
[exclaims] What evil
are you plotting? Stay away!
[FERN]
What a pain in the rear.
[Frieren snoring]
♪
[breathing shakily]
[chuckles softly]
[Fern blows]
[birds chirping]
[WIRBEL] I guess I couldn't
convince you after all.
You three should take the boat.
It would save you valuable time.
Ocean travel
is a tad too expensive.
It's fine.
Yeah.
My master's party trekked
through the Northern Plateau,
and so will we.
[Fern chuckles]
We're always accepting odd jobs.
And landing ourselves
in all manner of trouble.
Detours are a part
of our process.
[chuckles] You've carved out
quite the adventurous path
for yourselves,
and I won't block it.
So long.
I'm sure you'll reach
the far north eventually.
But until then, you take care.
Well, shall we be off?
♪
[♪ closing theme song playing]
[STARK]
That seems a bit extreme.
[EISEN] Talk about tyrannical.
[HEITER] Or maybe your joy
merely grows with our sorrow?
[HERO OF THE SOUTH] I'll die
without achieving my goal.
[HIMMEL]
At least we defeated a demon.
[FRIEREN]
"That's the Hero of the South."